So, are you interested on how to brush your teeth?
Well, my name is Michelle, and I'm a dental assistant with Solutionz, and I'm going to explain and show you, on how you can brush your teeth.
We have a great girl. She's going to demonstrate for us, on how to brush your teeth. It's pretty simple. First of all, you need the set of teeth, and you need a toothbrush, and a toothpaste.You want to place a small amount of toothpaste on to your toothbrush.
Just basically, you want to cover the bristles of your toothbrush.
Then, you're going to go ahead, and open for me, and actually bite down on your back teeth.
Back teeth, bite down, like this.
Good, just like that.
You're going to want to initially first, angle the bristles directly at like, somewhat of like a ninety degree angle, and you're going to place it, therefore the bristles are touching your gums and your teeth, and then you want to go around in a circular motion.
What you do not want to do, is go back and forth, or go up like this, because that will actually cause your gums to kind of swell, if you're going back and forth,and it will also cause your gums to recede,and then you'll start to become, having sensitive teeth, so you want to go in a circular motion.
That will ensure that you are removing all of the debris and bacteria, off of your teeth, and then you want to start in the front, and work your way towards the back, and then go ahead and open for me slightly, sweetie, and then when you're coming back towards your back teeth, it's always helpful that you close down just a bit, so therefore, it will release your TMJ joint muscle, to give you more room to brush back there, in a circular motion, so go ahead and close down for me.
There you go, just like that, and as you can see, I'm able to stick the toothbrush way back there, and you're making sure you're getting the very back part of your teeth, along with your gums,and you want to do that consistently, all throughout your mouth.
You want to do it on your upper arch, and also on your lower arch.
That will remove any of debris and bacteria from your gums, and then also you want to brush back and forth motion, on top of your teeth and that will remove any debris, and prevent you from having any cavities, and my name is Michelle, and I'm a dental assistant with Solutionz, and I just demonstrated for you on how to brush your teeth.